Whenever we talk about container orchestration, we always talk about Kubernetes, which is a very powerful
container orchestration tool.
Similarly, when we talk about cloud computing, we can always think of Microsoft Azure, which is one
of the leading cloud service providers in the market.
Now, when we combine these two, we get a service called Azure Kubernetes Service.
Which is a highly popular cloud container orchestration service.
But what is AKS and what does it do in this Azure Kubernetes service tutorial?
We'll be discussing this topic to the very core.
Now, let us go ahead and take a look at the agenda for the course.
Taking a look at the agenda, we'll be talking about following pointers.
Let's start by understanding what Azure Kubernetes is is .
But to understand that we would need to get into the details of topics like how software development
and deployment has evolved over time.
We'd also understand virtual machines and containers.
We'll understand how Kubernetes works to the core.
Then we'll discuss AKS and understand how it is different from Kubernetes.
Then we'd go ahead and take a look at a use case that tells us how as a Kubernetes service has helped
customers around the globe.
And finally, we would finish things off with a demo where we would understand how we can actually go
ahead and spawn container images using Azure Kubernetes service.
So let us not waste any time and quickly get started.