So first and foremost, let's try and understand what Asia Kubernetes services.
Now, I'm not going to get into the details of this service right away.
I'll just give you an introduction.
Azure Kubernetes Service is a fully managed container management service.
It is provided by Microsoft Azure, obviously, which is a very popular cloud service provider.
Recent stats also state that it is one of the leading public cloud service providers in the market.
So when you talk about Azure, Kubernetes, it is basically managed by Microsoft Azure.
What it does is it offers serverless, continuous integration and deployment experience.
Now what does that mean?
What we can do with it, we'll discuss all those things as we get into the details of Azure Kubernetes
service.
For now, we need to understand a few other concepts before we get to that point.
But to summarize few of its benefits, what Azure Kubernetes service does is it offers end to end deployment,
scalability and availability.
Now how do these things work?