We'll discuss how they all work.
But before that, let's try and understand what evolution of software development and deployment is
and how also it has evolved with time.
So we all know how applications were built and how they've progressed with time.
So if you talk about the popular ways in which software development and deployment has evolved, we
all think of waterfall model, agile model and DevOps.
Which is the current way in which we basically go ahead and deploy applications, or basically not only
develop but also maintain, monitor and deploy applications.
So let's try and understand all of these one by one.
Let's see how they evolved with time.
So when you talk about waterfall model and Agile model or DevOps.
They all have these three things which basically sets them apart.
The application architecture, their deployment or packaging, and finally, the application infrastructure
that we can think of.
Now, when you talk about the application architecture, the first one that is the waterfall model.
Which is known for its monolithic architectures, which is something that we came away from.
If you talk about current generation, we are more into the microservices model that is handled by a
DevOps.
So when you talk about waterfall, we had monolithic applications.
That means everything was inside a single application.
Your service, your applications, even your management tools and stuff like that, everything was inside
a single application.
And these kind of architectures were called monolithic architectures.
Now, with time, we had agile model where we had multi-tire applications.
Where some of your applications or some of the functionalities of your applications were handed over
to some other domain or to some other tier, and hence we had multiple tiers.
Say, for example, you would have your application tier in one place and you basically have a database
in another place, something like that.
And when you talk about DevOps, they took this functionality to a further classified architecture.
Where we had microservices or granular parts of your application that could function independently.
Now why do we need these kind of changes?
Why did we not offer monolithic applications?
Now, when we talk about monolithic applications, these were bulky and they weren't very rigid, not
easy to just go ahead and modify.
If you had modify it, you'd have to change the entire thing.
When you talk about agile, it gave you more flexibility how we had multiple tiers.
So if one of the tiers is not functioning right, so we could actually go ahead and work on that here,
and it would not affect the remaining functionality.
Three.
But when you talk about DevOps, when you talk about microservices in particular.
It basically breaks down your application into granular chunks where each of these applications performs
as a whole.
But you can think of them as an individual parts, which you can basically go ahead and function or
operate on individually.
And also ensure that you can basically make changes to these individual parts individually without affecting
the functioning of the entire application.
Now when we talk about deployment and packaging, we have different ways in which these applications
are hosted.
Or in which these different ways of software development and deployment works right.
So when you talk about deployment, packaging your waterfall model supported or supports your physical
servers, you have a physical server.
Similarly, when you talk about your DevOps or rather, we have agile first.
So when you talk about how you had your virtual servers.
Now, if you talk about cloud computing, yes, to some extent it supports virtualization.
But back in those days, virtual servers were a little different.
So if you talk about agile model, it basically lies on a deployment model, which is based on virtual
servers.
When you talk about microservices, on the other hand.
They are more based on containers kind of, and deployment is what I would say.
Similarly, if you go ahead and discuss their application infrastructure.
Now for your waterfall models, we had data centers that basically had all these applications being
hosted.
Right, your monolithic applications.
Similarly, when you talk about agile, we mostly move to the hosted platforms, right?
And when you talk about current microservices or your container infrastructure, we talk about cloud
hosting and that is why we've come up with this session where we'd be understanding how containers work
on top of cloud.
That is your Kubernetes orchestration tool.
In this case would be working on our Microsoft Azure cloud platform.
So I believe the evolution of development and deployment clear to you all now.
Let us now go ahead and understand or discuss some of the other bits that are on our plate.