Now, before we actually go ahead and understand how Kubernetes works and why are we talking about containers
and stuff?
We need to understand how containers are different from virtual machines.
Because virtual machines are something that people have been using, and many of them have migrated
to containers.
But why?
Because both of them, they have their benefits and reasons for these benefits.
So let us try and understand how a container is different from a virtual machine more than a comparison,
though, it is just understanding how they are different from each other.
Now this image should give you an understanding as to how these two things are different.
The one on the left hand side is your container, and on the right hand side you have your virtual machine.
Now when you talk about virtual machine, what a virtual machine does is on top of your server, it
lets you host your guest operating systems.
To give you an example, when you talk about a service or if you talk about a cloud platform like Microsoft
Azure.
Where you have Azure virtual machines, which again lets you spawn instances or virtual machines.
Now, these virtual machines or instances can have different guest OS.
Say, for example, if you launch a virtual machine that basically has guest OS of Linux.
And there's another virtual machine that has a guest OS of windows.
So we are talking about two different virtual machines or entities which function on the same server.
But they have different operating systems.
That means if I want an application to run in windows, I can do that using my virtual machine that
is windows in nature.
And similarly, if I want something to run on top of Linux, I can use the virtual machine that is Linux
in nature.
So that is what virtual machines are for you.
But there's a catch here when you talk about a virtual machine, you're talking about a server right
on top of that server, you'd be having your host operating system on which you'd be running a hypervisor.
Now, this is more of a middleware or a service that supports all the applications that are there on
top of it.
Including the operating system, the guest operating system that we are talking about.
Now, here, the problem is, as you can see, the virtual machines that you see on the left hand side.
They will have separate guest OS, they they'll have their bins, and then on top of that, they'll
be having the applications that are running.
Now, what is the disadvantage here?
Here, what happens is each time you have a virtual machine that is operating, we need to ensure that
there's a guest OS there, so there's a dependency on this.
And what this does is it makes it difficult for you to basically break this virtual machine from the
existing infrastructure architecture and make it run somewhere else.
Because this is a complicated process, but when you talk about containers, this is where the difference
lies.
Say, for example, I'll be having a Docker engine in this case, right?
It can be anything.
I mean, when you talk about Docker engine, it is a type of tool that provides you containers, OK?
So supports containers spawning for you, in simple words.
The other container tools as well.
But we are not here to discuss Docker
But just know Docker is one of the most popular container tools.
That is why you see Docker here.
So think of it as your container image of what you see there in the left hand side.
So you can see that there's a server host, you have your hypervisor, you have your guest OS, so guest
OS here is common, right?
So when you have a guest OS here, what that means is all the containers that would be running on top
of it would be running on the same guest OS.
So you do not have a dependency where basically you have to ensure that all the guest OS requirements
are also there in your container, so your container is more independent of the operating system.
The only concern here, though, is in case of containers.
You have to ensure that if you have one hypervisor or one Docker engine that is running for you.
Right in that Docker engine where there's a single guest OS.
In that case, you'll be running all your containers that are supported by that guest OS.
Now, if my guest OS is windows, I cannot expect myself to run Linux containers there.
I'm just giving you an example.
So there's a drawback then.
But the benefit here is since your applications, your bins and your library files are independent.
You can package them in a container and move them across easily so you can run it on other Docker engines
as well to support your claim.
What that does is since you have this freedom here.
Where you're not dependent on your guest OS or you do not have a guest OS inside your container, you
get certain benefits.
It makes your containers faster, makes them reliable and at the same time makes them efficient.
So that is basically what containers are, and that is how they different from virtual machine.
So I hope by now, the point here is clear to you all, and you've understood how these things function.
Great.
Let us now go ahead and understand the other bits.