So now let us try and understand what Kubernetes is right, because many of us know that it is a container
orchestration tool.
We always try to compare it with Docker, which may not be the right things to do or the best things
to do together.
Why is that?
Let's try and understand that as in what is Kubernetes, why do we need it?
And is it the same as Docker or not?
Okay, now.
There are few things that will tell us Why do we need Kubernetes and how it is different from Docker
is something that I would discuss in this bit  itself.
Now, when you talk about Kubernetes is it is used for container communication, now this is where .
It is different from Docker.
When you talk about Docker, it is something that lets you basically set up containers and work with
containers.
OK.
When you talk about Kubernetes is it is something that lets you manage these containers.
be it  your Docker containers or be it other kind of containers as well.
So that is what Kubernetes is does for you.
Now let us try and understand why do we need something like Kubernetes to manage these containers?
Be it a Docker container, or be it any other container when you talk about containers, they cannot communicate
with each other.
They need help to do that.
This is where a tool like kubernetes comes into picture.
Apart from that, if you go ahead, what containers do is they basically can be deployed as applications,
right as individual applications.
But since it is easier to deploy these applications thanks to containers, you cannot just go ahead
and deploy applications the way it suits.
You cannot just go ahead and deploy containers the way it suits you, right?
There has to be a process behind it.
You need to understand what containers to spawn, what to schedule, what to release, right?
and what to deploy rather.
So to do that, this is were again kubernetes comes into picture the third bit here is
Careful container management.
Now what do you mean by careful container management?
Again, is similar to what we discussed right as we talked about how deployment works.
Similarly, we also need to understand how container management works, right?
When you talk about containers, there are quite a few pointers that come into picture.
Now at the start, when I talked about Azure Kubernetes service, you realize that there were
certain pointers that talked about.
I mean, there were some highlights of features that on the first line that showed you it helps you
in better deployment.
Right?
And quite a few other things.
So when you talk about those pointers, right, what services like Kubernetes do is they ensure
that your deployment is happening properly, you are able to deploy multiple applications, right?
And you are also able to track whether these applications are up and functioning, whether one of these
applications instead, do you need to work on it, right?
So you get this kind of management when you talk about kubernetes, Fourth bit is Enable Autoscaling .
To give you an example, let's assume that you have an application that basically deals with three servers.
Now, let's assume that that application does very well.
Right?
In this case, you might need to scale that application.
Is it easier just to go and scale these applications?
No.
Right?
Because there could be a possibility that now you have to manage not just 3 servers, but you are required
to manage like hundreds of servers.
In that case, using a tool or using an orchestration tool rather like Kubernetes would help you ensure
that all your containers running in different 100 servers on top of these different 100 servers are functioning
properly.
So this is where auto scaling comes into picture.
What Kubernetes does is it gives an ability to auto scale applications in situations where manual intervention
is not needed, and that is what kubernetes does for you.
So these are some of the reasons why communities came into picture.
So yes, we had containers, but these were some of the drawbacks that containers had, and this is
what something like Kubernetes is lets you do.
Let us know ahead and understand what is Kubenetes is right.
So I have already explained what Kubenetes is this there's not a lot of different points that have left
to be explained.
So if you talk about Cuban, it is like it is an open source container management tool which automates
container deployment, container scaling and container load balancing.
So all the activities that we discuss about managing multiple servers, ensuring that all the containers
are working together, right, they're able to communicate with each other.
So basically, all the container management, it happens, all they orchestrate and it happens using
your Kubernetes, and that is what it does.
Okay.
What is one of the benefits it offers?
It works brilliantly with all cloud vendors.
It's a public hybrid or on premise.
And one of those popular cloud platforms, as I've mentioned, is Microsoft Azure, which would be discussing
as we move forward.
So what do you need to know more about?
Given it is now, these are some of the facts, right?
I mean, some of the things that might indeed you.
I'm not very sure about that, but if you talk about Kubernetes is it was developed by Google.
Okay.
So Google, as we know, brings in a big customer base, a big audience, right?
A big community to discuss.
And that is why this in itself is a big thing, because when you talk about something like Kuban, it
is.
It is going to have a huge community and that would mean that there's you support huge documentation
for you to work with.
It was developed using a programming language called Escola, and it entirely was built using it.
Apart from that to just to summarize what Kubernetes is it, you can think of it as a number of containers
that can be put into one logical unit so that you can simplify the process of managing these containers
and how they work.
OK.
So this is what you do when a thesis, in a nutshell.
Let's try and understand how the architecture of communities works and what are the components that
you should know about communities.
So this is what the basic architecture of Kubernetes is looks like.
OK, so you have your APIs, you have your Kubernetes master, you have your image registry, then you
have your notes, which basically are nothing but your applications.
So let's try and extend these one by one as in our bodies function.
OK.
So when you talk about the API, is the seelye and the UI, right?
The first thing that you need to do is you need to set up Kubernetes cluster, right?
So when you talk about it is cluster.
A cluster would be nothing but yard central management point using which you'll be managing all your
applications, all your different containers that hosted applications, right?
So first, what you do is you create this cluster, something that you can do by using your.
And then you can interact.
Or others can also interact with your cluster by using an API.
So, OK.
So yeah, API so is nothing.
But that basically ensures the authentication and the ID of the people are the resources interacting
with your when it is master of your Kubernetes cluster.
Okay.
Now, if you talk about Kubernetes cluster to stack your Kubernetes Lester, you are.
What you can see is you have the Cuban.
It is master like go in.
It is master is something that basically manages your containers and what you see on the left hand side,
the notes and stuff.
Right.
This is nothing but your work on it.
Now this is where you'll be having your applications that are actually running.
So, yeah, work notes would be implementing or running applications.
Your Kubernetes master, on the other hand, would basically be managing these applications and telling
you how to basically run these applications on top of it to understand this better.
Let's go ahead and take a look at this diagram that you have.
Okay, so what you see here is you see a Cuban, it is master, right?
And inside this Cuban, it is master.
There are quite a few other things as well.
We'll discuss those.
But what do you see on the screen are some key components that you need to know.
Okay.
So inside your Cuban, it is master.
You'd be having two important point does not as your application controller and your service.
Okay.
So when you talk about a replication controller, it is nothing but a resource that is owned by a master
that is Cuban.
It is master rate.
What it does is it ensures that the requested number of parts are running on nodes.
Always.
Okay, so your replication controller is something that controls the functioning, not controls.
It basically tells her working notes that keep the nodes or the parts running.
Now what are the parts and what do they do?
Well disclosed that.
Do not worry about that.
It's not very complicated, but that is what the replication controller does.
Apart from that, you have your service, which is nothing but again, an object on your master node,
right?
All you have given it is master idle that.
A light load balancing across replicated groups of parts.
Now let me try and make sense for these two by first explaining what I a. What I airports, right?
So when you talk about, you know, these are nothing but your work on notes which would be holding
your application.
In this case, you know, it can hold more than one application.
What we do is we basically classify our work and more into books, not by outside sub entities.
Right.
These are logical collections of the containers which need to interact with each other for the applications
to keep running.
OK.
And inside this box, you basically have your containers.
So that is what the infrastructure looks like.
You'll be having parts and which would be holding a logical set of containers that probably result in
a particular kind of application rate.
And you can have multiple such ports.
What you see here is you see what it tells you is a welcome node is nothing but a container, right?
So it can be another container to lesbian need not be docked.
But again, as I've mentioned, Docker is a popular tool, so you see it here.
So what you see here is basically a container rate which has multiple ports, and these multiple ports
are basically responsible for running your application.
And who controls all these applications, your Kubernetes master?
So assume a situation where you need to scale up a particular virtual machine, not a working machine,
in this case, a particular.
So how do you do that?
To do that, you basically have something like a load balancer, which helps to balance a load, right?
Either distributed or in case if you need scaling, it helps you scale your applications as well.
Right?
And then you have the replication controller that basically ensures that your application is running.
So what a replication controller does is it tells you onward that this application has to run, OK,
and who makes it run?
There's something called Kubelik now.
Inside every note, there would be another entity called Kubelik that Gilbert is responsible for running
your application.
So this is how you queue when it is architecture looks like, and this is how it functions.