Now we've understood what Kuberenets is and how it works.
Let us now go ahead and understand Azure Kubernetes Service.
Now to give you a brief about Azure Kubernetes Service.
As I've already mentioned, it is a Kubernetes Service.
that is hosted on the Azure cloud platform.
OK, so let me just explain that again so that we can go ahead and understand
how working of Azure Kubernetes happens.
So we've already Seen this slide, what is Azure Kubernetes Service?
But now that would make a lot more sense for you.
OK.
So what can happen or what Azure Kubernetes service offers to you?
Do you talk about Azure to start with?
It is a popular cloud service provider.
What that means is with Azure Kubernetes, or with Microsoft Azure.
You can basically have various services that help you in software development, planning, management,
right?
Be it your administrative practices, development practices or architectural practices related to software.
All these things can be hosted on a public server in this case, which again can be on Microsoft Azure
Cloud.
Now what it does is it basically gives you all these services that are needed to carry out all the actions
that I just mentioned where you can rent these resources or follow up as you go, model and use these
services to benefit your requirement.
OK.
Now, when you talk about a platform like Microsoft Azure, which again is a cloud platform, as I've
just mentioned, the possibility of dealing with applications are plenty.
or the possibilities rather
are plenty, so you can do so many things.
So what that does is that gives developers or application owners options to work with these applications
in numerous ways.
Okay.
It simplifies their complications, right?
Since you are talking about a platform like Microsoft Azure.
It helps you basically orchestrate quite a lot of activities be it managing your servers, infrastructure,
right?
Be it load balancing, auto scaling.
All these things can be controlled by using the cloud platform.
So what that does is that gives developers the added benefit or the application owners.
This added benefit and that is why what these cloud platforms are doing these days is they are encroaching
or basically covering different domains?
Be it your big data or DevOps analytics etc.
All these things are or can be implemented using these platforms.
Because when you talk about this cloud platforms, they are already owning various markets of software
development and application hosting.
OK.
So that is why having something like Kubernetes work on top of Azure is a benefit way, because some
of the complications that you would find difficult to implement using Kubernetes, can be controlled
by using Microsoft Azure.
And that is why you have these added benefits be it your end to end deployment,
be it your availability or scalability.
If you talk about some of the benefits that it actually offers, what it does is you pay only for the
node that you use.
That means last time I checked, Microsoft Azure did not charge you for your master node.
You only get charged for your work nodes that you used.
OK, your cluster upgrades are easier, so you do not have to worry about the patching part and stuff
like that.
Integration with various azure and other tools and services becomes easier.
Not just that, what you can also do is you can actually go and enforce various roles that are under
Azure policy across multiple clusters to have uniformity.
If you need to right? what, you can also do is you can scale Kubernetes and other nodes using autoscaler
that Microsoft Azure support, and you can even expand your scale even greater by scheduling your containers
on Azure containers.
So that is what Microsoft Azure Kubernetes Service provides you with.
Okay.
Let us now move further in this Azure Kubernetes Service and let's try and understand
some of the other important pointers, like how does the architecture of Azure Kubernetes services
works?
OK, to understand the working of AKS, or Azure Kubernetes Service, right?
You can see this diagram on the screen.
It's a fairly simple diagram and tells you what Azure Kubernetes Service does.
OK, so we've already seen how Azure Kubernetes architecture works Right?.
I mean, we know what all components it has and stuff like that.
This is a more detailed view.
So what you'll have is you'll have, again, a Kubernetes.
master master node or cluster is what you can call it.
OK.
So in this master node, the functionality would be same.
It would be controlling how the deployment and how the management of your containers work.
So basically, Azure will manage your master node it will basically help you control quite a few activities
that are there as a customer, you'd be managing the applications, only that you won't have support from Microsoft
Azure hope you.
Understand that now, if you talk about the control plane, what you have here is you have your API server.
now when you talk about your API server, what it does is it basically tells you how the underlying
Kubernetes APIs are exposed.
OK.
What this component basically does is it provides the interaction for your management tools be it your
Kubectl or the kubernetes dashboard.
Similarly, you have your etcd.
Now etcd basically what it does is it maintains the state of your kubernetes when I say the
state of Kubernetes.
I'm talking about the Kubernetes cluster and basically tells you control all the configuration that
is, there this thing is highly available and it is key value based in nature.
OK.
But you also have here is basically have a scheduler.
What is scheduler does is it lets you create and scale your applications to basically determine which
nodes can run on what workload and stuff like that.
OK.
And finally, you have the controller manager now.
This is an important bit again, what it does is it controls or overseas, a number of smaller controllers,
whether they're performing their actions or not.
And what it also helps you in doing is replicating the pods that you have and handling your nodal
operations as well.
So this is what your control plane does, and it is basically managed by Azure.
Now what is the benefit of having a Azure managed right since, Azure, is managing it?
you dont need to worry about the configuration part setting up part, right?
The cluster node is basically set up by Microsoft Azure, and that is what it simplifies.
Then the other bit is your customer managed bit, be it your Kubelet, your kube-proxy, your container
and container runtime to understand this better.
I think this diagram should draw a clearer or a better picture for you.
OK.
So basically, when you talk about your customer partner, the quite a few things that you need to know.
I've mentioned Kubelet, which basically lets you run your Pods.
Your pods are run by your kubelet.
That is what your Kubelet does.
OK.
There are other things as well that you need to know here.
You have your Azure virtual network interface now.
It is something that takes care of all the interface requirements that you might otherwise have.
OK.
And similarly, you have your kube-proxy, right?
kube-proxy again works together with your virtual network interface or basically your Azure virtual
network and tells you what needs to be done.
OK, now all these things, they reside on a virtual machine again.
So we've discussed all the differences and benefits.
of it.
So what Azure does is it basically launches a virtual machine for you.
On top of it, your containers would reside.
So when you talk about these containers again, these are nothing but the applications that are running
for you.
OK?
And these are the services that would help you actually implement or control all these applications
that are there you can actually go ahead and scale up your virtual machines to meet the requirements
of your application in different ways.
So this is how the working of a AKS is.
I mean, this is how the Master node works, and this is how your basically custom node or your worker
nodes work when you talk about AKS, will see these as we get into the demo.