But before that, let's go ahead and understand a use case, or see a use case as to how vehicle safety with
AKS is supported.
Now, when we say vehicle safety, we are talking about a use case that was set forth by ABC Automotive Company and ABC Automotive Company,
as we all know, is a very popular company which has numerous thousands of employees working across
the globe for meeting different technological needs of the world.
OK.
In this particular use case, what they thought of was the amount of accidents that happen due to wrong way
driving.
OK, and what they thought was could we find a solution that could basically help us overcome this bit
of problem?
OK, so what were the problems that they were facing when you talk about wrong with driving problems,
right?
What are the issues that we face because of wrongly driving?
There could be a lot of accidents, unplanned casualties and stuff like that.
But if I am to avoid wrong way driving using technology, it's a very tedious task.
The reason for that is what I can try and do here is I can basically set up an application that notifies
me of wrong way driving right.
But then for that to happen, I have to have a lot of data that is in real time.
And when I'm driving, my only way of getting data is by using cellphones and GPUs, right?
But then again, there are problems with these things when you talk about cell phones.
They basically function very well in a radius of five meters distance.
When you talk about their operational radians or, radius rather their limitations when you talk
about range and exchanging this data.
OK.
So you can transfer data to a larger audiences.
We see that through WhatsApp and stuff like that.
If you talk about GPS kind of data, we are talking about multiple points or multiple data that we
are dealing with, and to deal with them parallelly can be a difficult task.
So because of that ABC Automotive company felt that this was an impossible task to deal with.
Why?
In order to get the last piece of information out of the noisy sensor, data can be a problem.
And in order to develop a highly scalable and ultraflexible service to process this data in realtime can
also be a tedious task.
What they also figured out was to solve this problem.
They needed this data in realtime and in very short duration.
If we could do that, we could actually go ahead and save accidents and we could save these wrong way
driving incidents.
And that is why they decided to work with Microsoft Azure, which was that already supporting partner.
What they also did was they ensured that they did go ahead and accommodate, Azure Kubernetes
service in their infrastructure.
What does did was it ensured that ABC Automotive Company would get a repeatable, manageable clusters of containers.
And since they work in such short durations, do not have latencies in minutes, but rather in seconds,
they offered a simple form of services for them to work with.
And what that ensured was they had the average time to calculate that their driver is going the wrong
way or not in milliseconds.
So around 60 milliseconds, they could figure it out.
That is around a second where they could figure out that the driver was in the wrong way or not.
And that is what in basically Azure community service enabled them to do.
The major problem that is they had the time constraint that is something that held them on.
And because of that, they could come up with this wrong way, driving problem solution where they basically
used Microsoft Azure to host their data and basically Azure Kubernetes Service to basically help them
in simple provisioning, scaling of applications and ensuring that the real time data is made available
to the drivers within a span of 60 milliseconds, which again, is a big achievement.
So that is what AKS or Azure Kubernetes Service had to offer if you go to Microsoft Azure
website.
There are so many good use cases that talk about it.
So you might want to go out and take a look at that.