As far as the session goes, would go ahead and take a look at the demo and understand how they can
actually go ahead and set up an Azure Kubernetes Cluster and a lot more.
OK, so guys, let's go ahead and get into the demo part now.
This is how the Azure portal looks like, OK, I've signed into the Azure portal now for people who
are new to Microsoft Azure.
What Microsoft Azure does is it gives you an Azure portal where you can implement all the cloud related
activities that concern Microsoft Azure.
OK, so if you want to practice from scratch, it also offers a free tier account where you have a number
of services available free of cost.
OK.
Or rather, in case of Azure it works differently for AWS, you have those free services with Azure.
You have this $200 off credit that it gives you, so you can spend those two hundred dollars on creating
resources for eleven months duration post that those will expire.
So if you do not have an account, you can just go ahead and create a free tier account.
Fill in the details right and you should have this free Azure portal for your usage.
OK.
In my case, this is a paid account.
Again, this is the personal account.
It's called pay as you go.
In my case, in your case, it will be a free tire account, but the functionality would be similar for you
as.
The only thing is with the paid account, you have more.
Services available to you, and even the larger instances is something that you can actually go ahead
and spawn and use because you're paying for those right and the free tier, you don't have to worry
about paying for them, right?
So there are certain restrictions and limits that so do go ahead and register to Microsoft Azure Portal.
OK, now coming back to the demo part, what we are going to do now is we are going to create a Kubernetes
cluster and on top of that, we are going to deploy an application and the application would be a basic
pre-built app by Microsoft Azure.
We are not going to create a new app.
I will be sharing the code for the application so do not worry about that.
So we are just going to go ahead and use that pre-built core and we are going to deploy that code on
top of kubernetes.
cluster that we have.
OK.
So the main thing to note here is we have to see how easily the cluster is created.
We are not concerned about the orchestration process at all here.
Everything is taken care of by your Microsoft Azure and that is what we are going to look into.
So let's not waste any time.
Yes, quickly go ahead and get an instance in place, rather a cluster in place.
OK.
So to do that, we are going to click on this icon and to create a resource.
OK?
You can see all the service domains that are there for offering.
So I'm going to click on the containers one and click on Kubernetes service.
Once you do that, you'll see it'll be brought to this page and you'll get all the details right.
It gives managers your hosted Kubernetes environment, making it quick and easy for you to manage
containerised applications.
The main point is without having to container orchestrate or have any expertise in that.
OK.
It eliminates burden of ongoing operations and maintaining provisioning, upgrading.
scaling a resources rather which happens on demand here, so you don't have to worry about those
things.
So let's just go ahead and create a resource group.
So for people who do not know what a resource groups are resource group is, nothing.
But you can think of it as a small container or a folder where you put forth all the necessary things
that are important for your resource to work.
Now, in this case, the resource is Kubernetes so quite a few other integrities related to it would
be in the resource group.
OK, so let's just go ahead and create one.
So I'm going to click on create new.
Let's just say we have RGforDemo.
For the moment.
I'm going to give a simple name so that I can remember that.
Okay, so I'm going to say, OK, I'm going to create a cluster, I'm going to call it kubecluster.
OK, this is enough.
So Kube, let's call it Kubecluster.
OK?
And this is in place.
Where do I want it?
If you're using a Pay-As-You-Go model, there won't be any restrictions here.
If you're using free tier, there might be some.
OK.
So just select any reason that you want to do.
I'm going to randomly selected is and now what region you to be.
My region would be.
OK, let's pick this one.
And it would ask me, how many nodes do you want to create?
Let's create one.
Since it's a very simple demo, we do not need more nodes, OK?
We we've discussed what nodes are right?.
So that is what we are doing.
We are creating a node here where an application would run, basically.
So I'm going say review or lets go ahead and see if we have all the settings, node pools, authentication.
You have two options whether you want your server or rather your cloud platform to manage your identity
pools and basically create resources accordingly.
You can do that, or you can select a service principle, which is an older way to do it
where you use an Azuret Active Directory to do that.
So there's no rule here you can go for this one as well.
I'm just going to do this just because I've thought of showing it to you.
I selected that it does not hold a lot of impact on our demo.
OK.
Just going to say create and review.
So for creating this thing now, it will review all the requirements.
If the requirements are in place, what it will do is it will just go ahead and create your cluster
and put everything in place.
OK, so it says, do you want to create it now?
I'll say yes, create okay lets fresh and see whether our application is done.
Now it's still deploying.
Let's wait for this deployment to get in place and once it's done.
Yes, and go ahead and get these things in place after this, the process is very simple.
OK.
We are going to just go ahead and put in a certain set of commands and a job would be done.
So you don't have to wait for too long.
Post that?
OK.
There's just refresh it again and see whether it's in place normally takes a couple of minutes or could
take longer.
But it's a very easy deployment process.
So let me give you an idea as in what happens when you say that the deployment is happening.
So first, your kubernetes will actually go ahead and launch a Linux instance to start?
OK.
So once the Linux instance is in place, that is when will actually go ahead and put forth all our resources.
On top of it, in that Linux instance will set up a cluster.
Right all the integrities that we need an on top of the cluster our application would start working here.
In this case, it would probably set up a cache could be Redis as well.
We'll have to go ahead and look into it, whether that one.
OK.
And then accordingly, if we can go ahead and implement everything on top of that, but we don't have
to get into the complications of things.
It's a fairly simple process for us.
OK.
OK, let's just go ahead and refresh it once more.
No, it's done.
Your deployment has been complete is what it says that means we are good to go ahead and use the resource.
You can do other things as well.
On top of it, it is suggesting what you can do.
OK, so we are going to do one of these things.
Do not worry to just go to the resource in our case, OK?
And in this resource, you can see there's all the information that you need.
OK?
You'll get to know where it is hosted and stuff like that.
What kind of instance it is that it is located.
Everything.
One node pool is what you have, right?
So you have all the information to actually go ahead and connect to it.
So in your case, I'm hopeful that could happen faster than what you see in my case or on my screen
rather.
You see, cloud shell is up and running.
So let's just go ahead now and basically get credentials right, let's get the credentials or
merged cluster so that we can start using.
So how do we do that?
We use this command we say, "$az aks", OK?
And in this case, what we are going to do is we're going to say, get credentials "$az aks get-credentials".
OK, now the next thing is, what do we need resource group details.
When I say "$az aks get-credentials --resource
And I'm going to give the resource group name, which I am certain that we should see if we just scroll
up, OK?
So the resource name is RGforDemo that we used, OK?
Just For demo.
"$az aks get-credentials --resource-groupRGforDemo"
And what we also need is we need the name of the cluster.
And in this case, it is kubecluster.
$az aks get-credentials --resource-groupRGforDemo --name kubecluster
So you can do it, vice versa as well.
You don't have to go.
This order can start by giving in the details for your cluster and then detail for Resource Group.
I'm just going to hit the enter button now.
merged kubecluster as a current context, in this path is what it says.
OK, now let's just go ahead and get details for the node.
In this case, we know there's only one node, but you could be working on multiple nodes, right?
So in that case, you have to use this command "$kubectl.
You see.
You see, it is basically a client side interactive tool for interacting with your kubernetes.
OK, so that is what kubectl is all about.
OK.
And you say, get nodes "$kubectl get nodes".
If there are multiple nodes, it will give you multiple nodes.
If there's only one node, it will give you only one node.
So there you ago, you can see that there's one node that we have with this, OK?
We have all the details.
It's been running form, it says, right?
Because that is when we started the node.
OK, now the next thing is we are going to go ahead and select the YAML file where we've actually put
forward the details for our application right.
So how do we do that?
For that, we are going to go ahead and use this command. "$nano"
OK.
Now, no.
OK, space aside, the name of the application is the application that is related to voting.
So that is what I'm going to use this name and I'm going to say. "$nano azure-vote.yaml
OK.
I'm going to just paste the code here.
So basically, this is where you'll have all the details.
What is the API that is being used?
What is the container port right?
What is the memory that you are using?
What call are you making?
Right?
All those details are here.
Do not worry, I'll share the link to this piece of code.
If not, you can just look for Azure demos.
or getting started with Azure on your browser and you'll find this piece of code.
It's available everywhere.
You'll get this code on GitHub as well.
I do not own this code, so I will not take any right in saying that this is something that I've created.
It is a code that has been used and it is somebody else's work.
OK, so you may check out online for the details.
OK.
I'm just going to go ahead and paste my piece of code here.
OK?
When I say and all the code is again here with us.
OK, now how do I go ahead with it in this case?
I'm going to say save
I'm just going to say exit for now.
So we'll say yes.
So it will take me back to my cluster.
OK.
The next step is now what we are going to do is we are going to go ahead and call out this YAML file.
So once we do that, this is how we're going to do it.
We're going to say, "$kubectl apply -f azure-vote.yaml".
hit the enter button OK.
What was the name again, slash what?
Not Yemen.
Its friends created its backers created right.
So we need to see how it looks like, right?
So we are going to find out all the details as if we want to watch this app working.
We need details for it.
So we are just going to go ahead and use a command called as get service.
OK, so get services in place.
And in this case, again, my app name as you are what?
But this time I want different.
OK, so I'm going to say front.
And I'm going to say much.
And he and Dalton.
I basically made a blunder here, and that blunders.
We have to call this command true.
Typekit.
Right.
So in this case, again, we'll have to tape the remaining command again, so I'm just going to do it
quickly.
OK, get this.
As they are what?
Nice front.
Watch.
And you have external IP, so guys, at times what you see here.
Your external IP, if your system is very slow, which is in my case, but I don't know what happened,
it's aged only 85 seconds is what it is.
So normally it takes time for you to see this external IP, OK?
But luckily we can see it.
So I'm going to just copy it yet.
OK.
And I'm going to be.
And this way we should be able to see the application that we've created.
OK.
So it can see you can walk it.
One Let me work for dogs twice, thrice and I can just go ahead and reset it as well.
OK, so guys, this is how you actually go ahead and create a cluster.
OK.
A suggestion here would be you delete all the resources that is there.
Delete this one, delete the research group and also assert active directly so that you do not get just
if you want to see what we did here and how the performance went on, Azure lets you track all the working
as well, right?
If you want to take a look at the insights and stuff, if we click here, you'll have all those details
as well.
So there you go.
If I just refresh it, you should have all the details.
How long did we use the cluster?
This is where the users started.
Okay, so you get all these details that you want.
Chicken do that.
So that's it, I believe this demo is clear to you, people, and you got to know what things we worked
on, how we view these things and how basically your Kubernetes cluster works, OK?
So we've created a simple Kubernetes cluster and explored it.
And so when you go back, you just delete, just go to the resources and delete that resource group,
the cluster and the Active Directory, if any.
OK, so that's it.
From my end.
I hope you all enjoyed the session.
Thank you.
Bye bye.